<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ferrucc.io</title>
    <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ferrucc.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 17:34:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ferrucc.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 17:34:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/beauty/</guid>
      <description>One of the most interesting thought experiments one can do is exploring the history of aesthetics.
Human aesthetics change over time in ways that reflect progress.
How did people get bored of Greek tragedy? Why did chubby people become unattractive, when did people start liking squares on a canvas?
There was a moment when Dante&#39;s books were considered good. When realistic paintings like Church&#39;s Niagara were the pinnacle of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthcare should not be free</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 19:01:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/healthcare/</guid>
      <description>An axiomatic deduction of &amp;ldquo;Healthcare should not be free&amp;rdquo; starting from 5 agreeable axioms.
I like the idea of my site being a snapshot of my thoughts that I can point to people when having a discussion.
I don&#39;t like repeating the same arguments over and over.
So here are some of my thoughts on &amp;ldquo;Socialised Healthcare&amp;rdquo;[1] for wider exposure and future reference.
I&#39;ll start with 5 agreeable axioms and use them systematically to derive &amp;ldquo;Healthcare should not be free&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create boolean operators with Nand</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/booleans-from-nand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 21:34:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/booleans-from-nand/</guid>
      <description>Doing the nand2tetris course is an extremely enlightning experience into the world of computers.
The course starts from the simplest building block, the &amp;ldquo;NAND&amp;rdquo; operators and helps you step by step to building a modern, functioning computer, OS and tetris Game.
The NAnd block stands for Not And.
It takes two binary inputs, A and B and outputs true only if they both aren&#39;t true.
   A B Output     0 0 1   1 0    1 1 0   0 1 1    To derive the Not operation we have to find a way of using NAnd to have this output:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Embracing the tech bro meme</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/techbro-meme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 13:16:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/techbro-meme/</guid>
      <description>Every year I look back at myself one year back and cringe.
So as a gift to my future self, this is a collection of all my current habits
 I know I’m making a meme out of myself
 Note taking I take a lot of notes. After trying many apps I&#39;ve settled on Apple Notes. My thinking here is that the standard Notes app is here to stay. Even if I ever go broke I still should still be able to access it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s your company size?</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/company-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:53:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/company-size/</guid>
      <description>I set out to write this article by interviewing 40+ engineers at companies of all sizes.
  The main learning here was that organizational design and culture are a fascinating topic, and that they might be as important then company size when picking a job.
 Let&#39;s say you&#39;re early in your Software Engineer career.
You&#39;re a competent programmer looking for a change in working environment.
You’ve got 4 offers from four companies at different stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go, Chess - East, West</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/go-and-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 21:42:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/go-and-chess/</guid>
      <description>How two board games shape the concept of conflict in the western world and China.
Let&#39;s start with two photos:
Who won?
Try and guess who won in the two games.
In the first picture, even if you don&#39;t understand the game you can guess who won.
You can tell that the white is smashing the black into a corner.
And has more pieces in play.
Chess is a game based on domination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From idea to 100k uniques per week in two months</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/altacucina/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 15:06:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/altacucina/</guid>
      <description>This is a roundup of my experience as a 👨🏻‍🍳 Chef Technology Officer, building the tech side of Al.ta Cucina, the fastest growing recipe site in Italy!
In two months we went from idea 💡, to product:
The Story April 15th.
I just finished interviewing for a bunch of tech companies to move away from Italy.
I&#39;m trying to figure out where I want to go and what I want to do next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Development Gmail Account for Testing</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/create-a-testing-gmail-account/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 15:58:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/create-a-testing-gmail-account/</guid>
      <description>You are developing an app that uses emails, and need a testing account?
What&#39;s the fastest and easiest way to get a test account up and running?
By default Gmail doesn&#39;t support email importing from a file.
So the first step we&#39;ll have to go through is creating an Outlook email account here:
Create an Outlook Account
After creating an Outlook account we need to import data into it.
The reason I suggest you use Outlook is that it supports a format called .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Universal Basic Income a free lunch?</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/ubi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:41:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/ubi/</guid>
      <description>If there&#39;s something that I held as a deep belief growing up is that there is not such a thing as a free lunch.
I also developed an instinct to spot trends.
Mostly to find opportunities, but also for fun.
So when I stumbled upon Andrew Yang. I listened to a couple of his interviews and realised his ideas are powerful and bipartisan.
The way he talks makes him likable both on the left and on the right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music I like</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 20:47:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/music/</guid>
      <description>The music I like isn’t that ordinary, but I&#39;d say it&#39;s popular among developers in my age group.
I found that every time I meet someone in person that codes professionally the discussion at a certain point moves to “What do you listen when you code?”, “What is your favourite genre/artist?”.
Here&#39;s what developers from big cities in the 20-30 age group tend to listen.
  Take it easy my brother Charlie</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A functional IDE for React</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/a-new-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 20:43:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/a-new-ide/</guid>
      <description>6 years ago this video came out.
  At the time I couldn’t code yet.
This concept is still mind blowing to me.
Up until now I always thought about code as a collection of files, connected through imports.
But really we import functions, not files.
We use files to store code because they&#39;re a convenient way to serialize code. They&#39;re not the best representation, in fact functions might provide a better one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything I&#39;ve learned in 10 years of Blogging</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 20:57:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m 21, but I&#39;ve been blogging for almost 10 years.
I grew up doing this.
What I&#39;ve written on the internet has reached millions of people. Most of what I&#39;ve written is in Italian, but I was also quite successful when writing in english. My Quora profile, reached 400k people in three months.
Through blogging I had the opportunity to travel the world, getting free tickets to all the biggest music festivals (Ultra, Tomorrowland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The art of Sales, (Not So) Secrets from Old School Marketers</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/old-school-marketers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 11:44:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/old-school-marketers/</guid>
      <description>Marketing on the internet isn&#39;t much different from Marketing on any other medium.
So let&#39;s go back a hundred years to get some inspiration.
Inspiration from the 1920s After selling 100 million books of his series Little Blue Book marketer Julius Hadleman wrote a book analysing all the data he had collected.
The book title is &amp;ldquo;The First Hundred Million&amp;rdquo; and it came out in 1928 (email me if you need help finding it) and features an interesting collection of proven Titles that work and insights on what we&#39;re interested in reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VC is like Soviet Statism</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/vc-is-ussr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 23:37:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/vc-is-ussr/</guid>
      <description>VCs do everything you would expect the USSR would do, while being a private company.
VC Financing projects without asking too many questions. Sometimes people refer to this as VC welfare. If a company puts the right combination of &amp;ldquo;disruptive&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;blockchain&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; in their slides they receive funding. Showing some APIs, an app with users (real or fake) the money flows him.
With no real technical evaluation.
USSR Financing projects without asking too many questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sales for Cybersecurity Saas</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/sales-for-cybersecurity-saas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 19:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/sales-for-cybersecurity-saas/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been almost I month after I started working on Magehash
This is my first cybersecurity product I&#39;ve ever developed so I decided to share what I learned so far!
1) Selling Pain Points We can divide products into three different groups: candies, painkillers and vitamins.
We don&#39;t want to have much to do with candies.
Vitamins are interesting.
We love Painkillers.
For Cyber security software it&#39;s hard to be a painkiller as what we&#39;re generally trying to do is prevent attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know on Magecart Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/magecart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 19:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/magecart/</guid>
      <description>In the last month a group of hackers called Magecart came back striking in full force.
They first appeared in the news back in 2015 when RiskIQ found out they injected code in Magento&#39;s &amp;ldquo;Magecart&amp;rdquo; shopping software. Thus the name.
The attacks they organized have caused massive damages to hundreds, likely even thousands of companies like British Airways, Ticketmaster and even Newegg.
This group is specialized in card skimming payment forms on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from launching on Product Hunt</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/lessons-from-ph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 19:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/lessons-from-ph/</guid>
      <description>Two months ago I hadn&#39;t launched any solo project that got users.
Until lately everything I had ever done was with someone else, usually with a compatible skillset. The problem with this approach is that if someone on the team loses interest or is busy the project dies out.
As this happened a couple of times I decided to take some time and work on projects by myself.
The products I launched Klipped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dripform - No Bullshit Forms</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/dripform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 16:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/dripform/</guid>
      <description>A little more than two months ago Konstantin asked me how long would it take for me to develop something that would let him receive forms on his website as Telegram messages.
I wasn&#39;t sure how long it would take, but finding the task interesting I decided to just do it.
In an afternoon of work I made the first version of &amp;ldquo;Dripform&amp;rdquo;.
After making it I started exchanging ideas via email with Marc-Antoine who is working on a similar product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is wrong with Italy?</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/italy-s-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 19:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/italy-s-problems/</guid>
      <description>We now have a government in Italy.
Everyone around me is talking about this, so I figured out I might as well try to analyse what are the biggest problems the country is facing.
Here is a list of existential problems we face:
  Labor Market laws make it almost impossible or extremely costly to hire/fire anyone.
  Organised Crime, Tax evasion, Corruption and waste of public money plague the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Idea to MVP in a Saturday Night</title>
      <link>https://ferrucc.io/posts/6-dollar-mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2018 16:46:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ferrucc.io/posts/6-dollar-mvp/</guid>
      <description>Every time you finish writing a blog post you get that feeling that it&#39;s not ready to post it.
It&#39;s time for proofreading, but it&#39;s painful to proofread your own writings.
What is fun instead is reading someone else&#39;s writings.
So how great would it be if you could post your drafts somewhere, read and comment a couple of blog posts by people with your same interests, while your own get proofread by people like you?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>